好的，这是凝聚态课程的第二讲欢迎回来
okay this is the second lecture of the
condensed matter course welcome back
在第一次演讲后我们开始一群人之前的三件事
three quick things before we start a
bunch of people after the first lecture
问我这本书的标题是什么，以便他们可以在书店找到它
asked me what's the title of the book so
they can find it in the bookstore it's
牛津固态基础知识现在您可以找到它，这是我想要的第二件事
the Oxford solid state basics now you
can find it the second thing I want to
鼓励您使用留言板没人用过但还是有人勇敢
encourage you to use the message board
no one's used it yet someone be brave
发布第一条消息后，我保证您会发现它有用
post the first message once you get
going I promise you'll find it useful
第三件事，如果有任何问题，我上次强调的不够
the third thing I didn't emphasize this
enough last time if there's any problems
与课程中的任何错误错别字和作业设置书中的错别字
with the course any sort of error typos
and the homework sets typos in the book
我说的话如果在演讲中有误，请立即来找我
anything I say if it seems wrong in
lecture please come to me immediately
我可以发布更正，因此无法让所有人知道
and I can issue corrections and
therefore not get everyone is you know
尽可能让我们感到困惑，所以您只知道在
confused as much as we can so just you
know either post a message on the
留言板发送电子邮件演讲后抓住我，是的，我知道这很疯狂
message board send the email catch me
after lecture or yeah I know it's crazy
但你还是可以打给我，所以上次我们停下来谈话时
but you can call me maybe yeah anyway so
last time we we left off we were talking
关于固体的热容量，我们从玻尔兹曼图片开始
about heat capacity of solids and we
started with the Boltzmann picture of a
固体和Volta Mons图片两个月的图片都是固体中的原子
solid and Volta Mons picture both month
picture was that an atom in a solid
应该被认为是坐在谐波振荡器的底部
should be thought of as sitting in the
bottom of a harmonic oscillator
来回摆动，他能够从中得出定律
oscillating back and forth and from that
picture he was able to derive the law of
做一个小原子的小热容量是3 Kb，除了
do long petit heat capacity per atom is
3 Kb it's pretty good result except it
在低温下固体热容下降的情况不一致
didn't agree at low temperature where
the heat capacity of solids drops
爱因斯坦弄清楚发生了什么，他增加了量子力学，并且由于
Einstein figured out what was going on
he added quantum mechanics and due to
量子力学谐波振荡器的能级得到量化
quantum mechanics the energy levels of
the harmonic oscillator to get quantized
当温度降至量化能量以下时，振荡器得到
and when the temperature drops below the
quantization energy the oscillator gets
冻结了基态，热容下降了C
frozen his ground state and the heat
capacity drops C drops at low
温度在低T下下降，他的预测是温度应该下降
temperature drops at low T and his
prediction was it should drop
他的热容量理论成指数地拟合数据
exponentially exponentially his theory
of heat capacity fit the data pretty
很好，的确可以预测低温下的热容下降，但是
well and indeed it predicted this drop
of heat capacity at low temperature but
不幸的是实验说实验说低温
unfortunately experiment said experiment
said that at low temperature the heat
容量与T的立方成正比，且不呈指数下降，因此
capacities are proportional to T cubed
not dropping exponentially so that
带我们到今天的主题，如果我是1912年，那就是鸿沟
brings us to the subject of today which
is the divide if I was 1912 and the
直觉是你不能把固体看作是一堆原子
devised intuition was that you cannot
think of a solid as a bunch of atoms in
我们心脏的底部谐波很好，因为当一个原子移动时，它确实会
the bottom of our heart harmonic well
because when one atom moves it does get
被邻居推回原来的位置，但在此过程中
pushed back to its original position by
its neighbor but in the process it
推它的邻居，然后他的邻居推它的邻居，所以
pushes its neighbor and then his
neighbors pushes its neighbor and so
等等等等，实际上我们应该在想什么
forth and so on
so in fact what we should be thinking
固体中的振动实际上是波，尤其是
about is the vibration in a solid is
actually a wave and in particular
振动波已经响起，现在已经知道了如何
vibrational waves are sound now
something was already known about how
波一直在量子力学的影响下一直返回
waves behave under the influence of
quantum mechanics all the way back in
1899年，马克斯·普朗克（Max Planck）完成了黑体辐射的计算，
1899 Max Planck had done this black body
radiation calculation and when when Max
普朗克做了这个计算，他实际上不知道自己在做什么，他没有
Planck did this calculation he actually
had no idea what he was doing he didn't
甚至就像他在做什么一样，他说那是完全绝望的行为
even like what he was doing he said it
was a act of complete despair never
我真的很喜欢这个计算，但是十三年后，人们开始
really liked the calculation very much
but thirteen years later people started
了解有关量子力学和小子的一点点知识
to understand little bits and pieces
about quantum mechanics and plunks
原始的计算似乎更有意义
original calculations seem to make a lot
more sense
所以德拜认为我们应该做的就是量化声波
so Debye thought that what we should do
is we should quantize the sound waves
就像光一样，一般的想法是你知道这是现代的
just like light like light the general
idea is you know this is in modern
你知道朋克的语言不明白这一点，但我们明白
language you know plunk didn't
understand this but but we understand
现在来自爱因斯坦的工作，我们知道给定振荡器的能量
this now is from Einsteins work we know
that the energy of a given oscillator
将是H bar Omega乘以玻色系数βH bar Omega加上零
would be H bar Omega times the bose
factor beta H bar Omega plus the zero
点能量加上一半，所以如果我们有你知道的图片
point energy plus one half and so if we
have the the picture that the you know
我们现在解释普朗克，而我们所理解的是每个波动模式
of we interpret Planck as now and what
do by understood is that each wave mode
在米特尼克（Mitnick）的盒子里，将材料放在盒子里
in a box in a Mitnick you put your
material in a box
那个盒子里的每一波都应该当作振荡器，所以总的
each wave one in that box should be
treated as an oscillator so the total
盒子内的总能量e是所有波动模式的总和
energy e total inside your box is the
sum over all wave modes
该模式下的H-bar Omega乘以Lois factor beta H-bar的Omega
of h-bar Omega for that mode times Lois
factor beta H bar Omega for the mode
加1/2，您要做的就是对框中所有模式求和
plus 1/2 and all you have to do is sum
over all the modes in the box now the
原因这会给你带来不同于爱因斯坦的东西
reason this is going to give you
something different from what Einstein
曾经是因为每当您在框中有很多模式时，其中一些
had was because whenever you have a
bunch of modes in the box some of those
模式将是低温低能耗模式或低频模式
modes are going to be low temperature
low energy modes or low frequency modes
因此在爱因斯坦的计算中，当温度降至低于频率
so in Einstein's calculation when the
temperature dropped below the frequency
振荡器的热容量下降，但这里的想法是我们有一个
of the oscillator then the heat capacity
dropped but the idea here is we have a
框内模式中频率的整体分布，因此当降低
whole distribution of frequencies in the
modes in our box and so as we lower the
温度总是会有一些频率足够低的模式
temperature there will always be some
modes of low enough frequency that will
仍然有一些热容量，所以热容量不会下降
still have some heat capacity left so
the heat capacity won't drop
我们在低温下呈指数增长，这就是现在的直觉
exponentially as we go to low
temperature so that's the intuition now
朋克的所作所为和德拜的所作所为之间会有一些差异
there's going to be some differences
between what plunk did and what Debye
这样做是因为光在许多方面明显不同于声音，一种方式是
did because light is obviously different
from sound in many ways one way is that
光比声音快很多
light is of course a lot faster than
sound
但这只是数量上的差异，还有一些定性
but that's only sort of a quantitative
difference there's some more qualitative
我们将要处理的差异，特别是其中之一
differences that we're going to have to
deal with and one in particular
光与声音的区别在于光具有两种极化
light versus sound is that light has two
polarizations polarizations and sound
现在有三极分化，您会从enm记住，如果有一盏灯
has three polarizations now you'll
remember from your enm that if a light
是x方向的电磁波或电磁波
wave is or an electromagnetic wave of
any sort is going in the x direction the
电场必须在Y方向或Z方向上
electric field has to be in the Y
direction or the Z direction it can't be
如果在X方向上有声波，则X方向的声音就不会像
in the X direction sound is not like
that if a sound wave is going in the X
声波的极化方向可以是任何方向
direction the polarization of the sound
wave can be in any direction let me show
您可能最容易用电影解释这一点，所以让我向您展示
you it's probably easiest to explain
this with a movie so let me show you the
我所说的电影，这就是所谓的纵波
movie of what I mean by this this is
what's known as a longitudinal wave
这意味着原子在相同方向上来回运动
which means that the atoms are moving
back and forth in the same direction
波浪实际上正在前进，因此波浪正在X方向运动，并且
that the wave is actually going so the
wave is going the X direction and the
原子在X方向上来回移动，因此不会发生
atoms are moving back and forth in the X
direction so this doesn't occur for
光为光波在x方向上移动
light for light
the wave is going the x-direction the
电磁场始终指向z方向的y方向
electromagnetic field is always pointing
in the y direction of the z direction
与光更相似的是所谓的横波，其中光是
more similar to light is what's known as
a transverse wave where the light is
好在波向X方向传播的地方，但是原子实际上是
good where the wave is going in the X
direction but the atoms are actually
可以在Y方向或Z方向上来回移动
moving back and forth in the Y direction
or the Z direction okay so with sound
实际上，原子可以移动三个极化
you can actually have three
polarizations the atoms can be moving in
任意方向，而光只能指向两个方向
any direction whereas light the electric
field has to point in only two possible
方向是明确的，是的，很好，所以我们必须跟踪
directions is that clear yeah okay good
so we're gonna have to keep track of the
事实上，我们对光有三种极化，而对树液只有两种极化
fact that we have three polarizations
for light and only two for sap the way
声音的三个极化，光的只有两个极化
around three polarization for sound and
only two for light there's a couple of
我们还将做的事情将是近似的
things we're gonna also do which are
going to be approximations which are
使我们的生活更简单的一个是，我们将假设速度
going to make our life simpler one is
that we're going to assume the velocity
声音V的声音与拉深的极化无关，这是
of sound V sound is independent of
polarization in depth of pull this is
实际上并非如此，几乎总是横向模式会更慢
not actually true in reality almost
always the transverse mode is slower it
速度比纵向模式低，但实际上不是
has a lower velocity than the
longitudinal mode but it's actually not
要正确地处理它要复杂得多，但是您不会学到很多东西
so much more complicated to treat this
properly but you don't learn a whole lot
做得更好，我认为本书中有一项练习
more from doing it more properly I think
there's an exercise in the book that
要求您做得更正确，但我们将假设所有声音
asks you to do it more properly but
we're just going to assume all sound
波浪具有相同的速度，而与它们是否
waves have the same same velocity
independent of whether they're
纵向或横向，只要我们假设不是
longitudinal or transverse as long as
we're assuming things which are not
真的正确，我们还可以假设V声音与方向无关
really correct we might as well assume V
sound is independent of direction of
经常不正确的方向也经常
direction
which is often not true also frequently
当您拥有真正的固体时，声音的速度取决于
when you have a real solid the speed of
sound depends on which direction the
当然，我们将在本学期稍后再讨论这一点，但
solid you're going we'll discuss that a
little bit more later on in the term but
再说一遍，如果您更正确地对待它，那不是很多
again it's something that if you treat
it more properly it's not that much
更努力，您不会从中学到很多东西，所以我们不会做
harder and you don't learn so much more
from doing it so we're not going to do
它更合适，但请记住，我们正在做出这些近似值
it more properly but just keep in mind
that we are making these approximations
现在，如果您还记得去年所做的小节计算
now if you remember back to plunks
calculation which you did last year
您要担心的第一件事是计算一个盒子中的所有模式
the first thing you had to worry about
was counting all of the modes in a box
听起来有点熟悉，我们会去吗
does that sound familiar
a little bit familiar we're gonna go
再次通过它，因为它很重要，我们将使用很多
through that again because it's
important and we're gonna use a lot of
这个机制很多是今年要做很多其他事情，所以值得
the a lot of the mechanism is to do many
other things this year so it's worth
通过，所以这在计数盒子中的波浪数上有点
going through so this is a little aside
on counting waves in a box counting
波浪模式我猜框模式，所以这很难从一维开始
waves modes I guess modes in box so this
is hard to start with a one dimensional
box 1d box，让我们在这里画一个一维的盒子
box 1d box so let's draw the one
dimensional box here it is it has some
长度L，我们可以在硬壁边界的盒子中写下波浪
length L we can write down a wave in
that box with hard wall boundary
您知道，L的条件和PI x在两端都变为0，这是因为
conditions and PI x over L as you know
comes to 0 at both ends because of the
硬壁边界条件，这是写下来的完美好方法
hard wall boundary conditions and this
is a perfectly good way to write down
框中每个不同的正整数n的波动n都不同
the waves in the box for every different
positive integer n you have a different
wave模式还可以，但不是我们要做的是我们要做的
wave mode that's okay but it's not not
what we're gonna do what we're gonna do
相反，我们将使用所谓的周期性边界条件
is instead we're going to use what's
known as periodic boundary conditions
您可能在去年讨论了周期性边界条件
you may have discussed this last year
periodic boundary conditions boundaries
也称为天生冯卡门边界条件天生冯卡曼卡门卡门
also known as born von-karman boundary
conditions born von Karman Carmen Carmen
出生是马克思的其中之一出生是量子力学的创造者之一
born was one of the Max born was one of
the creators of quantum mechanics and
西奥多·冯·卡曼曾是非常重要的数学家，马克斯·博恩也很
Theodore von Karman was a very important
mathematician Max Born is also very
很重要，因为他是奥利维亚·牛顿·约翰的祖父，她是
significant because he was Olivia
newton-john's grandfather she's an
重要的流行歌星，如果您不认识她，她对我这一代人很重要
important pop star if you don't know her
she was important for my generation at
无论如何，这样的话人们对我的印象并不足够深刻
any rate so anyway people don't see me
sufficiently impressed by that statement
是的，实际上还是可以的，所以周期性边界条件的想法是
it's it's actually it's anyway ok so the
idea of a periodic boundary condition is
我们要取长为L的盒子，然后将其包裹成一个圆圈
we're gonna take our box of length L and
we're going to wrap it up into a circle
L的周长，然后我们将测量X
of circumference L then we're gonna
measure X going around the box in this
这样的方式，我们之所以这样做，是因为一旦我们这样做，
way like that and the reason we're doing
this is because once we do this the
波浪可以采用e到ikx的形式，我们不必处理正弦波，
waves can take the form e to the ikx we
don't have to work with sines and
余弦如果我们在一个圆上有一个周期框，则可以使用指数的
cosines if we have a periodic box in a
circle we can use Exponential's and if
到现在为止，您还没有学过指数只是
you haven't learned already by this time
in your career Exponential's are just a
现在，当我们编写一个符号时，使用符号和共同符号要容易得多
lot easier to work with
signs and co-signs now when we write a
向ikx挥动e，我们必须要小心一点，因为坐标X和
wave e to the ikx we have to be a little
bit careful because the coordinate X and
X到L的坐标实际上是相同的坐标（如果走了L的距离）
the coordinate X plus L are actually the
same coordinate if you go a distance L
在盒子周围，您会回到完全相同的点，因此该波形
around the the box you get back to
exactly the same point so this wave form
无论是插入X还是x加L都必须完全相同，所以我们最好有您
must be exactly the same whether we plug
in X or x plus L so we better have you
知道这是否有意义，我们最好让ikx的e等于e
know if this is going to make sense we
better have e to the ikx equal to e to
IKX加L ok，否则i KS的e等于1或K必须为2 PI
the I K X plus L ok or otherwise e to
the i KS to equal 1 or K has to be 2 PI
在L上乘以整数N，该整数可以是正数或负数，或者
over L times an integer N and that
integer can be positive or negative or
是我们喜欢的东西，到目前为止，每个人都满意
is whatever we like ok
everyone happy with that so far so good
好的，这意味着允许之间的间隔
ok so this means that the spacing
between allowed between between allowed
允许的国际象棋国际象棋是2 PI，超过L ll是我们循环的周长，
allowed Ches Ches is 2 PI over L ll
being the circumference of our loop and
特别是如果我们必须对所有k求和，我们可以替换该总和
in particular if we ever have to sum
over all the k's we can replace that sum
通过积分衰减乘以2 pi的L倍，您是否经历过
by an integral decay times a factor of L
over 2 pi did you go through this
去年的争论有点不错，好吧，我们将大量使用它
argument last year a little bit yes well
ok we're going to use it an awful lot
今年，这就是为什么我要再次经历它，因为它很重要
this year so that's why I'm going
through it again because it's important
现在我们当然不是生活在一个维度中，所以我们必须考虑
now we of course don't live in one
dimension so we have to think as
多维的人，我们必须在多个维度进行思考，因此在3D中
multi-dimensional people we have to
think in multiple dimensions so in 3d
我们要乘L乘L乘L乘L
we're gonna take an L by L by L periodic
box photic box and at this point you
可能会开始有点不高兴，因为没有L
might start to be a little bit upset
because there's no such thing as an L by
在现实世界中，L到L的周期性盒子必须有一个盒子
L by L periodic box in the real world
you would have to have a box for which
如果您在任何方向上走了L距离，您都会回到正确的位置
if you went a distance L in any
direction you came back to exactly where
您从三个维度入手，您无法构建这样的东西，他们只是没有
you started in three dimensions you
can't build such a thing they just don't
存在，所以为什么要这样做，尽管重点是
exist so why is it we're going to do
this though the point is
实际上，对于系统边界几乎做什么都不重要
doesn't actually matter what you do with
the boundaries of your system for almost
您实际上对计算感兴趣的任何数量，例如热容量
any quantity you're actually interested
in calculating such as the heat capacity
您可以在一个很小的区域内进行本地测量
it's something that you could measure
locally just in a small region of the
实际的物理系统，所以对
actual physical system so it doesn't
matter what you would do with the
边界可能非常远，因此您可以使用硬墙边界
boundaries which could be very very far
away so you can use hard wall boundary
您可以使用周期性边界条件您可以使用任何其他类型的条件
conditions you can use periodic boundary
conditions you can use any other type of
边界条件对我们来说很方便，使用它们很方便
boundary condition which is convenient
and for us it's convenient to use these
周期性边界条件，我们将摆脱它的原因是
periodic boundary conditions and we're
going to get away with it the reason we
想要使用这些周期性边界条件是因为
want to use these periodic boundary
conditions is because then the waves
看起来像Evi K矢量点X矢量，它是指数的
will look like Evi K vector dot X vector
it's an exponential Exponential's are
易于合作，这就是为什么我们在每个仍然开心的人中都这样做
easy to work with and that's why we're
doing it everyone that's still happy
很好，所以在三个维度上，K必须是L倍的2 PI
with that okay good so in three
dimensions K has to be 2 PI over L times
整数和x + y + Z，因此，如果我们对K个向量求和，则可以替换
integers and x + y + Z and so if we ever
have a sum over K vectors we can replace
L与2 PI乘以积分DK X积分DK y积分的总和
that sum with L over 2 PI cubed times
the integral DK X integral DK y integral
DK Z或我们通常会写的另一种方式将写为
DK Z or another way that we will most
usually write this will write this as
系统的体积乘以2个PI立方上的积分d 3k，我们将得到
the volume of the system times the
integral d 3k over 2 PI cubed and we'll
看到这个因子体积积分D 3k超过2 PI的立方，可能会看到它a
see this factored volume integral D 3k
over 2 PI cubed probably see it a
在我们还没做好之前，今年有一百次，所以我们要做的是
hundred times this year before we're
done okay so what we're going to do is
我们将使用刚刚学到的关于对盒中的波进行计数的知识来应用
we're going to use what we just learned
about counting waves in a box to apply
这里的方程式，所以这里有一些超模
to this equation here so there's some
over modes here I then write sum over
模式将成为我们模式中所有可能的K向量的总和，但是
modes is going to become the sum over
all possible K vectors for our modes but
然后乘以因子3，因子3来自三个极化
then times a factor of 3 and the factor
of 3 is from the three polarizations we
可以有一个纵向或两个横向极化，然后这个
can have one longitudinal or two
transverse polarizations and then this
总而言之，我们将在这里使用该定律将其转换为整数，所以现在我们
sum we're going to use this law here to
convert it into an integral so now we
自从我们有了3个2 PI的体积积分后，体积积分d 3k的三个因子
have three factor of the volume integral
d 3k over 2 PI cubed now since we've
在这里假设一切都是各向同性的
assumed over here
everything is isotropic and in other
单词速度与方向无关，我们可以采用这三个
words velocities are independent of
direction we can then take this three
维笛卡尔积分并将其转换为球极积分，所以我们
dimensional Cartesian integral and turn
it into a spherical polar integral so we
有三倍的体积，让我们在这里拉出2个PI立方体，然后
have three times the volume let's pull
out the 2 PI cubed here and then we have
熟悉的从0到无穷大的整数4 pi K平方DK
integral 4 pi K squared
DK from 0 to infinity as this familiar
4 pi是球形方向上的积分是3 aqua极性
the 4 pi is the integral over the
spherical directions yes 3 aqua polar
因为我们正在考虑声音，所以最终协调每个人对此感到满意
coordinates everyone's happy with that
finally since we're thinking about sound
您去年或去年在流体课程中可能学到的声音
for sound you've probably learned in
your fluids course last year or last
最后一项频率与波矢成正比
last term frequency is proportional to
the wave vector and the proportionality
常数是声音的速度，所以我们只需要改变积分
constant is the velocity velocity of the
sound so let's just change that integral
变成一个积分的超频率，而不是积分的超波矢量，这样
into an integral over frequency instead
of an integral over wave vector so that
成为一些因素，让我们在楼上将4 pi取出
becomes a pull out some factors here
let's pull out a 4 pi upstairs we have a
2 PI楼下立方体我想我们楼下有速度立方体，然后我们
2 PI cubed downstairs I guess we have
velocity cubed downstairs and then we
有一个整数0到无穷大的Omega平方D Omega，我要写
have an integral 0 to infinity Omega
squared D Omega and I'm going to write
那就是定义一个Omega D Omega 0到无穷大的数量G而这个G
that as just defining a quantity G of
Omega D Omega 0 to infinity and this G
欧米茄（Omega）只是这些常数中的一小部分，我将坚持在一起
of Omega is just a bunch of those
constants I'm going to stick together so
我想我楼上有12 12 pi，楼下有2 PI我想我
I guess I have 12 12 pi upstairs and I
have 2 PI cubed downstairs I guess I
楼下有一个速度立方体，然后楼上有一个体积，我要
have a velocity cube downstairs and then
I have a volume upstairs and I'm gonna
以一种棘手的方式将音量写在楼上，我将其写为
write the volume upstairs in sort of a
tricky way I'm gonna write it as the
原子数除以楼下体积即密度，然后
number of atoms divided by the volume
downstairs that's the density and then
楼上的原子数会很方便，然后我需要
the number of atoms upstairs that's
going to be convenient and then I need
欧米茄平方欧米茄平方，所以这里的这个量称为
also that Omega squared Omega squared so
this quantity here is known as which I
把它放在这里欧米茄G被称为欧米茄G
put it over here G of Omega is known as
G of Omega is
被称为国家密度，我认为您去年遇到了
known as the density of states and I
think you ran into this last year when
你做了黑体辐射，国家密度的想法是
you did blackbody radiation the idea of
a density of states is that it is
基本上，您在给定频率下有多少种这些模式
basically how many of these modes you
have at a given frequency in particular
G Omega D Omega等于频率介于
G Omega D Omega equals number of modes
with frequency frequency between between
欧米茄（Omega）和欧米茄（Omega）加D欧米茄（Omega），因此，如果您想对
Omega and Omega plus D Omega so if you
want to sum over all the modes in the
系统，而不是仅汇总所有模式，而是集成
system instead of just summing all the
modes what you do is you integrate over
所有频率乘以每个频率下的模式数量
all frequencies times the number of
modes at each frequency okay sort of a
方便的做事方式实际上我也将简化一点
convenient way to do things I'm actually
also going to simplify this a little bit
通过定义另一个方便的数量，我将重写
further by defining another convenient
quantity I'm gonna rewrite this G of
欧米茄的Omega G，因为我要写出N个原子然后
Omega G of Omega as I'm gonna write it
as pull out the N number of atoms then
九个欧米茄平方超过欧米茄D立方，所以我将欧米茄D定义为立方
nine Omega squared over Omega D cubed so
I'm defining Omega D cubed here to be a
那些常数在一起的一堆Omega D立方是六倍平方平方倍
bunch of those constants stuck together
Omega D cubed is six pi squared times
体积密度乘以声音速度的密度，这称为
the density number over volume times
velocity of sound cubed this is known as
至少在目前，按频率划分的德比频率
the Debye frequency after mister du by
frequency and at least for now
我们只是将其视为我们拥有的一堆常数
we're just going to think of it as this
bunch of constants that we've
方便定义，因此写GI的意思会更容易
conveniently defined so it's easier to
write G I mean in a moment will give it
一个更重要的含义，但现在只是那些常数
a more important meaning but for now
it's just those bunch of constants okay
因此，完成所有这些操作之后，我们可以在顶部
so having done all of that we can then
weigh up there at the very top of the
板上，我们将能量表示为所有模式的总和
board we have the expression for the
energy as a sum over all of the modes so
实际上，也许我会把它放在这里，所以我不必将其滚动到
I'm actually maybe I'll put it over here
so I don't have to scroll that off the
最重要的一点，所以我们现在将能量总计
top of the board
so we'll now write the energy the total
在给定温度下的能量，而不是将其写为所有模式的总和
energy at a given temperature instead of
writing it as a sum over all the modes
我将把它写成等于频率的整数
I'm going to write it as an
integral over frequencies equals
从零到无穷大的积分D欧米茄G欧米茄是所有模式下的总和
integral D Omega from zero to infinity
G Omega that's the sum over all modes by
频率积分，我们想要积分的是H bar Omega
integrating over frequency and the thing
that we want to integrate is H bar Omega
弓箭因子beta H栏欧米茄加一半好吧人们对此感到满意
bows factor beta H bar Omega plus
one-half okay people happy with that
我们正在做什么是是也许是好的好吧好吧，这就是表达
what we're doing yes yes maybe yeah okay
good all right so this is the expression
我们将尝试评估，如果您真的非常关注
that we're gonna try to evaluate and if
you're paying really close attention
你已经对我不高兴了，因为它实际上是无限的
you'll be upset with me
already because it's actually infinite
盒子中的总能量是无限的，之所以无限，是因为
this total energy in the box is infinite
and the reason it's infinite is because
加上一半的乘积，再看乘以一半的乘积
of this plus one-half look at what the
plus one-half multiplies it multiplies
欧米茄的Omega G因子与Omega平方成正比，所以它是
the factor Omega G of Omega is
proportional to Omega squared so it's
欧米茄从零到无穷大的立方积分
the integral of Omega cubed from zero to
infinity
那是无限的，所以你可能会认为这是一个问题
that's infinite so that's kind of it you
might think that's kind of a problem
实际上，它并没有因为他们不知道而去买或买东西
actually it didn't bother to buy or
plunk because they didn't know about
零点能量，所以他们从不写下这个加一半，但不是
zero-point energy so they never wrote
down this plus one-half but it's not
出于多种原因会困扰我们，这主要是因为它不会继续
gonna bother us either for a number of
reasons the main reason it's not going
困扰我们是因为它给了我们无限的数量，但这是无限的
to bother us is because it gives us an
infinite quantity but it's an infinite
与温度无关的数量是唯一的位置
quantity that's independent of
temperature the only place in this
我们要在一天结束时在此处表达温度的表达式
expression where temperature occurs is
right here at the end of the day we want
热容，是能量相对于温度的导数
heat capacity which is the derivative of
the energy with respect to temperature
所以我们将不得不根据温度来区分这件事
so we're gonna have to differentiate
this thing with respect to temperature
而1/​​2将会消失，因为它与温度无关，所以
and the 1/2 is going to go away because
it's temperature independent so it's
给我们无限但与温度无关的贡献，所以我们不会
giving us an infinite but temperature
independent contribution so we don't
稍等一下，我们会看到另一个原因
care about it actually in a few moments
we're gonna see another reason why we're
不会在意那1/2，但现在我们只知道它不会
not gonna care about that 1/2 but for
now we'll just realize it's not going to
改变我们对热容的表达吧
change our expression for the heat
capacity all right
所以现在我们可以将状态密度插入此方程式中，所以让我们
so now we can plug in the density of
states into this equation here so let's
这样做，我们得到9，我将拉起H栏
do that
so we get 9 and I'll pull up the H bar
从那边经过立方体的Omega 2
from over there
there's Omega 2 by cubed here cubed
楼下，然后剩下的东西整合了来自
downstairs and then the thing we have
left to integrate integral D Omega from
0到无穷大，楼上有一个欧米茄立方体，然后
0 to infinity
there's Omega cubed upstairs and then
βH bar欧米茄的玻色因子e
the bose factor e to the beta H bar
Omega
-剩下的看起来有点丑陋，但是我们可以将其取整
- one is left that looks a little bit
ugly but we can take this integral we
可以通过写x等于beta H bar Omega来简化它，然后
can simplify it a little bit by writing
x equals beta H bar Omega and then the
积分在beta H条上变为1，是该积分的第四倍
integral turns into 1 over beta H bar to
the fourth times this integral integral
DX从0到X的无穷大，将e立方化为X减1，我保证你没有人
DX from 0 to infinity of X cubed e to
the X minus 1 and I promise you no one
曾经要你评估这个积分，只是一些数字
is ever going to ask you to evaluate
this integral it's just some number the
这个数字恰好是PI到15的第四个，如果您真的想知道
number happens to be PI to the fourth
over 15 and if you really want to know
该数字来自您，它位于您知道的其中之一的附录中
where that number comes from you it's in
the you know appendix of one of the
本书的各个章节，当有人说您可以阅读本书的内容时，您是否讨厌它？
chapters of the book and don't you hate
it when someone says you can go read the
本书，但实际上并不是那么重要，它只是给了我们一些重要的信息
book but in fact it's not so important
it just gives us a number the important
事情是它给了我们一些已知的数字，因此我们可以将该数字放入并获得
thing is it gives us some known number
so we can put that number in and get the
最终结果是，盒子中的总能量为9，KBT为
end result that the energy the total
energy in the box is 9 and KBT to the
第四部分除以H bar欧米茄Debye立方倍乘以该因子部分的第四部分
fourth here divided by H bar Omega Debye
cubed times this factor part of the 4th
超过15很好，然后我们当然可以将其区分以获得热量
over 15 okay good and then of course we
can differentiate this to get the heat
热容量是DT，没关系，所以在H bar Omega 2 bi上为n KB KB T
capacity heat capacity is de DT and ok
so it's n KB KB T over H bar Omega 2 bi
立方，然后我想12 PI到5的第四个PI让我们开始吧
cubed and then I guess 12 PI to the
fourth over 5 let's so that's the heat
能力，因此有几件事对此做出评论，这使得
capacity and so a couple of things to
comment about this it makes this
首先令人兴奋，它与T的立方成正比，就像by想要的
exciting first of all it's proportional
to T cubed just like the by wanted you
如预期那样获得热容量的T立方依赖关系
get the T cubed dependence of the heat
capacity as expected it shouldn't be
令人惊讶的是，您获得了T立方热容，因为您从
surprising that you get this T cubed
heat capacity because you remember from
您去年做的黑体辐射计算表明
the blackbody radiation calculation you
did last year that the energy of
辐射您计算的盒子中的波能量与T成正比
radiation the energy of waves in a box
that you calculated is proportional to T
到第四，你应该期望能量是第四的T
to the fourth you should have expected
the energy to be T to the fourth and
然后您将其微分一次，就得到T的立方，这就是为什么Debye
then you differentiate it once and you
get T cubed so this is why Debye
期望以相同的方式对待海浪
expected that by treating the waves the
same way
我们处理了辐射我们将得到T立方定律
we treated radiation we would get the T
cubed law furthermore there's something
这个公式真的很令人兴奋，那就是没有免费的
really exciting about this formula here
and that is that there's no free
参数记得当爱因斯坦进行计算时，他有这个频率
parameters remember when Einstein did
his calculation he had this frequency
这个爱因斯坦频率他不知道如何振荡的频率
this Einstein frequency the oscillator
frequency which he didn't know how to
提出这个频率，他只是将其适合实验以尝试使其达到目标
come up with this frequency he just fit
it to the experiment to try to make it
一切看起来都很不错，这里没有免费参数Omega Debye，这里的问题由
all look nice here there's no free
parameter Omega Debye here is fixed by
密度和声速，所以一切都固定在这里
the density and the sound velocity so
everything is fixed here and if and if
计算这个量，然后将其与低温热量进行比较
you calculate this quantity and you
compare it to low temperature heat
实际上大多数材料的容量都非常一致，但是
capacity of most materials it actually
actually agrees extremely well but
不幸的是，就像您知道您永远不会免费得到任何东西一样，我们仍然有
unfortunately like you know you never
get anything for free so we still have a
高T时的问题我们希望在N上做长C的定律是3 KB
problem problem at high T we want the
law of do long Petite C over N is 3 KB
我们没有得到在所有温度下都得到T的立方，这就是
and we didn't get that we got T cubed at
all temperatures here and this is where
BI不得不稍微挠一下脑袋，然后想我好吗
the BI had to actually scratch his head
a little bit and think okay what did I
如果您进行此计算，会偶然出错
do wrong
incidentally if you do this calculation
对于电磁辐射，真的是一直到第四能量的T
for electromagnetic radiation it really
is T to the fourth energy all the way up
到任意高温，如您所知，我们知道
to arbitrarily high temperature where as
you know in a solid we know that the
固体在某些高温下的热容会给我们
heat capacity of the solid at some high
temperature is going to give us just
三个KB不会被T切丁，所以在这里我们必须偏离塞子
three KB it's not going to be T cubed so
here we have to deviate from plunks
计算中，我们必须做些不同于那次沉思的事情
calculation we have to do something
different from what it was that plunk
做到了，然后就明白了他错在哪里
did and plunk and the by understood that
where he was going wrong where he was
出问题了，您知道他必须考虑这3来自何处
going wrong you know he has to think
about where this 3 comes from where is
3中的3来自原子可以在3中移动的事实
this 3 from the 3 comes from the fact
that the atom can move in three
每个原子向三个可能方向移动的方向
directions each atom moves in three
possible directions you can figure this
原子具有的3个自由度以及他有多少个自由度
3 degrees of freedom that the atom has
and how many degrees of freedom did he
在他的盒子里算好模式总数他算出的模式数
count in his box well the total number
of modes number of modes that he counted
他的从0到无穷大的积分G Omega D Omega和Omega G都和Omega一样
his integral from 0 to infinity G Omega
D Omega and G of Omega goes as Omega
平方，您将其集成到其中，并给您无限，所以他
squared you integrate that into
and that gives you infinity so he
数了无数的自由度，他说好吧，我是
counted an infinite number of degrees of
freedom and he said well wait I'm I
在盒子里计算了无数种模式，但是有有限数量的
counted an infinite number of modes in
the box but there's a finite number of
每个原子可以在三个方向上移动的自由度，不应有
degrees of freedom each atom can move in
three directions and there shouldn't be
盒子里的自由度远不止这些，所以我必须以某种方式解决这个问题
more than that many degrees of freedom
in my box so somehow I have to fix that
问题，使Box仅具有固定数量的自由度
problem and make the Box have only a
fixed number of degrees of freedom not
无限的自由度，所以他是怎么做到的
an infinite number of degrees of freedom
so how did he do that impose a cutoff so
他要做的是宣布一些截止频率的欧米茄
what he's going to do is he's going to
declare some frequency cutoff Omega
截止G Omega D Omega这样盒子里现在正好有三种n模式
cutoff G Omega D Omega such that there
are exactly three n modes in the box now
这是一个临时解决方案，有点怪异，所以他正在做的是
this is an ad-hoc solution and it's kind
of a little weird so what he's doing is
他是说我们将所有这些波动模式都放在一个盒子里，当您到达某个
he's saying we have all these wave modes
in a box and when you get to some a
称为截止频率的频率，高于该频率就没有波模
frequency known as the cutoff frequency
above that there are no more wave modes
离开时，您没有声音移动到高于该频率的位置，似乎不再是
left you have no sound moves above this
above this frequency anymore seems a
学期后期有点奇怪，我们会发现它可能不像
little strange later in the term we're
gonna see it's maybe not as strange as
我们以为是在那时，也许看起来有些奇怪，但他
we thought but at then at that time
maybe it seems a little odd but he's
无论如何都会这样做，所以无论如何我们都会跟随他，
gonna do it anyway so we're gonna do
this anyway we're gonna follow him and
看看会发生什么我们要做的第一件事就是我们必须弄清楚这是什么
see what happens first thing we need to
do is we have to figure out what this
截止频率将是这样，它将恰好给我们三个n
cutoff frequency is going to be such
it's going to give us exactly three n
模式，所以让我们很好地计算一下这个东西，然后将其插入Omega的G中
modes so let's calculate this thing well
plug in G of Omega so plug in G of Omega
在这里，有一个9，还有一个欧米茄2，由立方积分0到欧米茄截止
here so there's a nine and there's Omega
two by cubed integral 0 to Omega cutoff
欧米茄（Omega）平方D欧米茄（Omega），所以我只是在那儿插入了Omega的G，然后开始
Omega squared D Omega so I just plugged
in G of Omega there and then let's do
该积分，我们得到3，Omega切割成立方体，而Omega Debye切割成立方体，再见
that integral and we get 3 and Omega cut
off cubed over Omega Debye cubed goodbye
立方，我们希望它等于3 N，为了使它成为真，我们更好
cubed and we want this to equal 3 N and
in order for that to be true we better
选择欧米茄截止值等于欧米茄2双，这就是为什么我碰巧选择那些
choose Omega cutoff equal to Omega 2 bi
okay that's why I happen to choose those
如果Omega 2乘以Omega 2，则特定的常数是截止频率，如果
particular constants as being Omega 2 by
Omega 2 by is the cutoff frequency if
您以德拜频率切断模式
you cut off your modes at the Debye
frequency
仅计数比您拥有的德拜频率更低的频率的模式
only count modes at lower frequencies
than the Debye frequency you have
精确的3n模式好吧，所以现在我们要回到这个方程式
exactly 3n modes okay all right so now
we're gonna go back to this equation
在这里，我们现在将框内的总能量重写为
over here and we're going to rewrite the
total energy in the box now as the
积分计数模式从无穷大到现在只有Omega D by G
integral counting up modes not to
infinity now up only up to Omega D by G
欧米茄，然后是玻色系数βH吧，欧米茄，然后再加上1/2零点
Omega and then the bose factor beta H
bar Omega and then plus 1/2 zero-point
能量，您会注意到，因为我们已经切断了许多模式
energy and you'll notice now because
we've cut off our number of modes this
项不再发散，它是一个有限的零点能量项，这使我们
term no longer diverges it's a finite
zero-point energy term and that makes us
有点快乐，但是我们实际上可以忽略它
a little bit happier but again we can
actually ignore it
删除它，因为它与温度无关，是温度
drop this because it's temperature
independent it's a temperature
独立的零点能量，我们还是要区分事物
independent zero-point energy we're
going to differentiate the thing anyway
所以我们真的不在乎它只是为了给我们一些整体
so we don't really care about it it's
just going to give us some overall
不断变化的能量不是很有趣，所以我们要
constant shift and the energy which
isn't very interesting so we're gonna
放下它，然后这个表达应该给我们能量
drop that anyway ok and then this
expression should give us the energy in
盒子或盒子中的热容量
the box or the heat capacity in the box
once we differentiate it at any
我们只是通过在此处插入温度来选择温度，但这很有用
temperature we choose just by plugging
the temperature in here but it's useful
查看各种限制，因此第一个限制是低温限制，
to look at various limits so the first
limit is low temperature limit and by
我的意思是说KBT比H-bar Omega Debye少得多，在这个限制下，我们得到了
that I mean KBT much less than h-bar
omega Debye and in this limit we get the
与之前的结果相同
same result
same result as we had before this result
正是在这里，这什么都没有改变，为什么那是原因，什么都没有
here exactly this nothing changes
why is that well the reason nothing
变化是因为在低温下，玻色系数很快消失
changes is because at low temperature
this Bose factor vanishes very quickly
在您接近Debye频率时的频率Bose系数
with frequency by the time you're up
near the Debye frequency the Bose factor
基本上是零，所以在Debye切断它并不重要
is essentially zero anyway so it doesn't
matter if you cut it off at the Debye
频率或分频的两倍或分频的一半
frequency or twice the divide frequency
or half the divided frequency the
那时那个时候被积数是零，所以你不必担心
integrand is zero anyway by that time so
you just you don't have to worry about
截止温度在低温下根本没有任何作用，因此您仍然
the cutoff at all at low temperature the
cutoff isn't doing anything so you still
得到我们想要的T立方热容，但是在高温下
get the T cubed heat capacity which is
what we want but at high temperature at
高温，我们会有一些不同的感觉，好吧，让我们看一下
high temperature we have something
different well okay so let's look at the
高温下的玻色系数beta H bar欧米茄很小
Bose factor at high temperature at high
temperature beta H bar Omega is a small
我们可以扩展指数，所以我们得到
number
we can expand the exponential so we get
1加beta H吧Omega加婴儿床减去1，所以取消的那些使我们比beta H高1
1 plus beta H bar Omega plus cot minus 1
so the ones cancel we get 1 over beta H
bar Omega或我们得到Bo的因数被替换，Bo的KB超过H bar
bar Omega or we get the Bo's factor is
replaced and Bo's becomes KBT over H bar
欧米茄，所以如果我们考虑这个Bo因子并将其插入该能量中
Omega so if we then take this Bo's
factor and plug it into that energy
表达式再次降低零点能量现在能量为整数零
expression again dropping the zero point
energy the energy is now integral zero
对不起，我要截止到截止日D Omega G Omega然后我们有H
to sorry to I'll make it to by up to the
cutoff D Omega G Omega then we have H
bar Omega，然后我们得到的Bose系数是H bar Omega的KBT
bar Omega and then we have the bose
factor which is KBT over H bar Omega the
H bar欧米茄（Omega）被取消，我们通过拉出KBT获得能量
H bar Omega is cancel and we get the
energy being given by pull out the KBT
D Omega G Omega对Omega D的积分是0，这里的积分是
and integral 0 to Omega D by D Omega G
Omega and this integral here has been
设计为正好为3 n，所以我们得到的能量为3，KBT
designed to give us exactly 3 n so we
get the energy in the box is 3 and KBT
或热容量为3 km KB
or the heat capacity is 3 km KB the law
of do long petite so by implementing
这个截止德拜设法获得负载温度热容为T
this cutoff Debye managed to get the
loads temperatures heat capacity is T
立方高温热容仍是做长娇小法则
cubed the high temperature heat capacity
is still the law of do long petite so
很好，让我们看一些实际数据，这就是热量
that's pretty good let's look at some
actual data so this is the heat capacity
在很宽的温度范围内以及高温下的银
of silver over a broad range of
temperature and up at high temperature
您会发现这符合长时间做娇小且低温的定律
you see it's it's converging to the law
of do long petite and at low temperature
它大约是T立方体，德拜理论与实验相符
it's roughly T cubed and the Debye
Theory agrees with the experiment
非常非常好，您可以在同一地块的同一幅画上看到
extremely extremely well you can see on
the same on the same plot there's the
爱因斯坦理论非常适合，但不如
Einstein theory which fits pretty good
but not quite as well as to by
特别是在低温下，但在其他方面确实很重要
particularly at low temperature and but
on additional really important
从爱因斯坦到迪拜的改进是，德拜没有免费参数
improvement from Einstein to Dubai is
that Debye has no free parameters then
在德拜理论中，一切都是通过声速来固定的
everything is fixed in the Debye theory
by just the velocity of sound in the
密度，所以不知道你不能乱扔东西，你不能调整它
density so there's no knowing you can't
muck around you can't adjust things it
只是适合自己，所以这是一个真正的结果，似乎非常同意
just fits by itself so it's a really
result and seems to agree extremely well
通过实验，但我们仍然遇到问题，仍然是错误的或仍然可以
with the experiment but we still have
problems still wrong or still well okay
仍然错误的一件事是截断实际上是临时的临时特别是我们
things that are still wrong one is the
cutoff is really ad hoc cutoff ad hoc we
只是弥补了这一点，我的意思是这是有动机的，
just sort of made this up I mean it was
a motivated it was a motivated thing to
这是一件很明智的事情，但我们没有做到这一点
do it was an intelligent thing to do but
we didn't it wasn't really justified
另一件事是错误的是我们使用与波成比例的Omega
another thing that's kind of wrong is
that we used Omega proportional to wave
向量声音定律这里的频率将与波向量成比例，但是
vector the sound law here the frequency
will be proportional to wave vector but
我们在高K下使用它，这不是真的
we use this at high K and that's not
true
声音很小K到很小的时候就会出现长波长现象
sound is a small K a long wavelength
phenomenon when you go to very small
波长或非常高的波矢，这不再是真的，所以这很合理
wavelengths or very high wave vector
this is no longer true so this was sort
一个问题，我们在地毯下刷了什么，顺便说一句
of a problem that we brushed under the
rug and what and incidentally the the
当您在Debye频率附近起床时，我们正在谈论的波长
wavelengths we're talking about when you
get up near the Debye frequency the
波长接近原子间的间距，所以我们在谈论
wavelengths are close to the inter
atomic spacing so we're talking about
非常小的波长或非常高的波矢，我们不能
really really small wavelengths or
really high wave vectors and we can't
真的再考虑那种情况下的声音，所以这是一个问题
在地毯下刷另一件事是，德拜是不正确的，这是不正确的
brushed under the rug another thing is
that Debye is not exact it's not exact
对于任何材料，虽然从该图可以明显看出它非常好，
for any material although it's pretty
good as is obvious from that plot and
第三或第四种金属是不同的金属对于我们的金属也是不同的
third or fourth metals are different
metals are different well for metals we
正如我上次提到的，金属具有低温比热C
have for metals as I mentioned last time
we have low temperature specific heat C
正比于立方的alpha t加gamma T，其中debye预测了alpha，因此
proportional to alpha t cubed plus gamma
T where alpha is predicted by Debye so
如果您进行了德拜理论，则系数α正确，但是
if you did the Debye Theory you would
get the coefficient alpha correct but
您根本不会得到伽马，所以这只是一个大问题，我们现在不
you wouldn't get gamma at all so this is
just a big question right now we don't
知道那是哪里来的，所以我们必须弄清楚
know where that's where that's coming
from so we have to figure that out and
在几节课中，我们将很好地知道这是从哪里来的，但是对于
in a few lectures time we'll have a good
idea where that's coming from but for
现在，这可能是个谜，您现在可以对我说，但请稍候
now it's it's a bit of a mystery now you
might say to me at this point but wait a
第二不是银不应该是金属
second isn't silver a metal shouldn't I
see
低温下的线性热容确实银是金属，
a linear heat capacity at low
temperature indeed silver is a metal and
您应该会在低温下看到线性热容量，但必须注意
you should see a linear heat capacity at
low temperature but you have to look at
很难看到它，所以它被炸得非常低
it pretty hard to see it so this is
blown up the very very low temperature
一二四或五开尔文或类似一二的政权
regime sort of one two four or five
Kelvin or something like that one two
你知道凯尔文（Kelvin）我猜，这里绘制的是热容
you know for Kelvin I guess and what's
plotted here is the heat capacity
除以温度作为温度平方的函数，如果是
divided by the temperature as a function
of temperature squared if it was a
纯净立方定律，那么这条线将是一条直线并且将相交
purity cube law then this line would be
a straight line and it would intersect
零它显然不相交零它与有限截距相交
zero it obviously doesn't intersect zero
it intersects a finite intercept which
实际上是伽玛，所以有一个非常小的术语伽玛这个术语是
is in fact gamma so there's a very very
small term gamma this term gamma is
很小，但显然必须仔细测量才能看到
pretty small but it's clearly there you
have to measure pretty carefully to see
它，但是没关系，所以在这一点上，我们已经说完了
it but it's there okay all right so at
this point we're sort of done talking
关于固体的振动一会儿，我们稍后再回来讨论
about vibrations in solids for a little
while we'll come back to them later in
当我们尝试更好地理解这些术语时
the term when we do a little bit of a
better job trying to understand these
事情，但是现在我们把它放在一边，我们将要换档
things but for now we've putting this
aside and we're going to switch gears
然后开始谈论金属，因为金属在以下方面明显不同
and start talking about metals because
metals are obviously different in
这是一种与众不同但又与众不同的方式
several ways this is one way that
they're different but they're different
还有很多其他方式，这就是众所周知的
in many other ways as well and this is
something that was this was known to
古代人都知道，甚至您可能在穴居人时代就知道了
known to the ancients even you know
probably in caveman days they they knew
他们发现在地面上发现的一些材料
that there were some materials they
found on the ground that just looked
与其他材料不同，到公元前4000年，
different from other materials and by
4000 BC people were able to work with
某些金属之类的东西，例如铜，然后几千年后
certain metals things like like copper
and then a couple thousand years later
他们能够使用铁，每次能够指挥
they were able to work with iron and
each time they were able to command a
特殊的金属并与之合作，他们能够使新事物做新
particular metal and work with it they
were able to make new things do new
使用新技术并真正改变人类的历史，因此您
devices new technologies and really
change the history of humankind so you
知道从金属犁开始金属剑金属盔甲金属战
know starting with metal plows metal
swords metal armor metal warfare of all
然后在金属机器上进行排序，您就会拥有金属摩天大楼，
sorts then later on metal machines you
have metal skyscrapers you know the
核时代是由重金属和重金属音乐带来的
nuclear age was brought in by you know
heavy metals and heavy metal music very
也很重要，但您知道金属的历史
important also
but metals you know the history of
金属以某种方式追溯了人类的历史，您知道直到
metals in some way traces the history of
mankind and you know it wasn't until
确实在1800年代后期，有人最遥远的主意是什么导致金属
really the late 1800s that anyone had
the remotest idea what causes metals to
与众不同，在2000年代之前，我们才真正了解
be different and really in 2000's before
we really understood the properties of
重要的是，您必须记住您对我们了解
matter
you have to remember you know for us the
金属的定义属性将是导电
the defining property of a metal is
going to be that it conducts electricity
非金属则不知道，但我们什至不知道什么是电
and nonmetals don't but we didn't even
know what what electricity was until the
1800年代末，JJ汤普森（JJ Thompson）发现电子或
late 1800s it was 1897 before JJ
Thompson discovered the electron or what
他称那小小的电荷小球可以在
he called the small corpuscle of charge
that can move around freely in the
金属，并可能通过足够高的电压从金属中弹出，并且
metals and could be ejected out of the
metal by a sufficiently high voltage and
这张金属的照片实际上是所有这些的容器
with this picture of the metal really
being sort of a container for all these
电子在周围跑来跑去成为人们的自然选择
electrons running around there became a
natural thing for people to do which was
考虑将这些电子作为一种气体围绕着电子而流动
to consider these electrons running
around as a gas a gas of electrons and
这就是保罗·德鲁德（Paul drew de）做的，被称为德鲁德（Drude）一种金属金属理论
this is what Paul drew de did was known
as Drude a theory of metals of metals
Arjuna的运输理论适用于金属，实际上特别是
well Arjuna theory of transport applies
to metals and it's actually particularly
很好，它起作用了，这引起了理论，这是一个非常粗糙的经典动力学理论
good it works this drew the theory it's
a very crude classical kinetic theory
电子的电子动力学原理与电子的电子动力学原理非常相似
kinetic theory of electrons of electrons
very much like the kinetic theory of
您去年在热物理课程中研究的气体有效
gases that you studied last year in your
thermal physics course it works
尽管它非常粗糙，但效果非常好
extremely well despite the fact that
it's very crude it works extremely well
在很多方面对半导体特别有利，所以我们将
for a lot of things particularly well
for semiconductors and so we're going to
首先使用这种美容理论攻击您知道金属中的电子传输
attack you know electron transport in in
metals using this beauty Theory first
然后我们会在以后进行改进，例如您去年的动力学理论
and then we'll improve on it later so as
with your last year's kinetic theory we
为了使动力学理论可行，有两个假设
have a couple of assumptions assume in
order to get kinetic theory going one
从头到尾都有一个散射时间tau应该看起来很熟悉
there's a scattering time scattering
time tau should look familiar from last
的年份，我们的意思是
year by which we mean that the
probability of scattering probability of
时间T或时间DT上的scat等于tau上的DT
scat in time T or in time DT is equal to
DT over tau now this probably looks
从去年开始熟悉气体动力学理论以来，我们
familiar from last year when you did
kinetic theory of gases last year we
需要连接它们的气体，您甚至可以预测散射时间tau是多少
need to connect their gases you can even
predict what the scattering time tau is
根据原子的大小以及它们移动的速度以及类似的东西
based on the size of the atoms and how
fast they're moving and things like that
首先，由于几个原因，今年我们不会那么幸运
this year we're not going to be so lucky
for a couple reasons first of all it
不清楚电子的散射截面应该是多少
isn't clear what the scattering
cross-section of the electron should be
因为电子通过远距离库仑与事物相互作用
because the electrons interact with
things via long-range Coulomb
互动，使他们可以从很远的地方分散开来
interaction so they could they could
scatter from things very far away
可能会导致很难弄清楚是什么的另一件事
potentially another thing that's going
to make it difficult to figure out what
tau的意思是电子除了可以散布其他很多东西
tau is is that the electron can scatter
off of lots of other things besides just
它们可以从质子中散射出来的其他电子，也可以从杂质中散射出来
other electrons they can scatter off of
protons it can scatter off of impurities
它可以散布在金属中的任何东西，所以对我们来说
it can scatter off of anything in it
happens to be in the metal so for us
这个散射时间tau只是一个现象学参数，
this scattering time tau is just gonna
be a phenomenological parameter the
我们要假设的第二件事是在散射之后
second thing we're going to assume is
after scattering after a scattering
分散后的事件，我们会将最终动量设置为零，因此您
event after scatter we will set the
final momentum equal to zero so you
想像一下，您知道某事沿其移动，然后散布
imagine something you know something
moving along it scatters and then its
最终动量为零，现在不正确
final momentum is zero now that's not
right
通常，当某物散布时，其最终动量在某些情况下会随机消失
generally when something scatters its
final momentum goes off randomly in some
随机方向，但作为矢量的平均值
random direction but on average as a
vector the average of the vector after
散射几乎接近零，因为它可能会消失
the scattering is pretty close to zero
because it can go off in any possible
方向，这将足以使我们能够做出
direction and that's going to be good
enough for us to be able to make
进展您去年可能没有的第三点是
progress the Third Point which you
probably didn't have last year is that
电子之间的散射之间的散射事件之间应看到E
between scattering events between
scatters the electron should see sees E
和B场（如果它们恰好在那），所以如果您要施加电场
and B field if they happen to be there
so if you're applying an electric field
电子会由于电场而加速到您的金属或
to your metal the electron will
accelerate due to the electric field or
它会由于似乎很自然的磁场而弯曲，就像
it will curve due to the magnetic field
which seems rather natural just like the
电子，我们生活在真空中，所以考虑到这三个假设，我们可以
electron we're living in a vacuum okay
so given these three assumptions we can
想象我们从在时间T具有动量P的电子开始，所以T为P
imagine that we start with an electron
that has momentum P at time T so P of T
动量很好，在时间T时间T很明显，然后我们想
is momentum well okay that's obvious at
time T time T and then we'd like to
计算在时间T和DT时的动量是什么意思
calculate what is the momentum at time T
plus DT I mean in some ways we're asking
在T加上DT时对动量的期望是什么，但我们将其视为
what the expectation of the momentum at
time T plus DT but we'll treat it as the
在时间T和DT时的实际动量
actual momentum at time T plus DT well
there's two things that can happen in
在时间T时间T加DT之间，可能约为负1
between time T
time T plus DT with probably one minus
DT超过tau的概率，这是不散射概率的概率
DT over tau this is the probability this
is probability of not scattering prob of
不分散如果不分散，就不分散，然后发生什么好
not scattering not scattering if it does
not scatter then what happens well then
它具有区域动量加上对其施加的力乘以DT和
it has a regional momentum plus whatever
force is applied to it times DT and
没关系，这就是说DP DT（如果不分散）是F
that's just okay this is just saying
that DP DT if it doesn't scatter is F
牛顿定律很好，但除此之外，
Newton's law good but in addition to
this there's also the probability a
DT相对于T的分散概率，如果分散，我们给出
probability DT over T that it does
scatter and if it does scatter we give
动量为零，所以这是不分散它的可能性
it momentum zero okay so this is a
probability of not scattering it
由于施加在其上的力，其照常加速，如果它确实散开，我们
accelerates as usual due to the force
applied to it and if it does scatter we
散射好之后，将其动量设为零，那么我们可以做一点
give it momentum zero at after the
scattering okay then we can do a little
稍微重新排列一下，实际上也许我们先将其相乘
bit of rearrangement here well actually
maybe let's multiply this out first so
这是T的P加F DT减去tau上的P，然后是DT，然后
this is then P of T plus F DT minus P
over tau and then there's DT and then
有加号DT的平方，加上一些重新排列，我们可以写
there's plus order DT squared and with a
little bit of rearrangement we can write
DP DT应该是T处的P + DT减去DT上的T的P，如果我对我大吼
DP DT which should be P at T plus DT
minus P of T over DT yell at me if I
开始难以理解的写作，你知道它是否真的太痛苦了
start writing incomprehensibly
you know if it really gets too painful
只是对那边的方程式进行了一些重排
and just doing a little bit of a
rearrangement on that equation up there
并将这个组合放在一起，我们得到F但在tau上减去P，所以让我
and putting together this combination we
get F but minus P over tau so let me
重写它，因为这是一个重要的方程DP DT等于力
rewrite this because this is an
important equation DP DT equals force
在tau上减去T，这就是juda传输方程，以及什么力
minus T over tau this is known as the
juda transport equation and what force
你应该很好地使用它的力量是通常的洛伦兹力量吗
are you supposed to use in it well the
force is the usual Lorentz force force
是负e e加V叉B，所以无论用什么力
is a minus e
e plus V cross B so whatever force the
电子感觉进入那个方程，所以看起来很像
electron feels goes into that that
equation so this looks a lot like
DP DT中的牛顿方程等于F是牛顿方程，但我们有
Newton's equation in DP DT equals F is
Newton's equation but we have this
右边的附加术语，看起来像是阻力，是
additional term on the right hand side
which looks like a drag force it's a
与当前动量相反的力
force going in the opposite direction
from its current momentum so whichever
方向，力朝相反的方向拉，所以
direction it's going the force is
pulling in the opposite direction so
让我们实际上在这里做一个非常快速的计算让我们考虑一下
let's actually do a really quick
calculation here let's consider consider
在系统中没有电场或磁场的情况下，
the case where there's no no electric or
magnetic fields in your system so you're
不施加任何电场或磁场，则DP DT为负
not applying any electric or magnetic
field then you just have DP DT is minus
P over tau可以解决，方法是说T的P是一些花生
P over tau which you can solve by saying
P of T is some peanuts some initial
动量e减去tau的负T，所以告诉我们，如果我
momentum e to the minus T over tau so
that tells us that the momentum if I
有一个电子和一些初始动量一起运动，这个散射项
have an electron moving along with some
initial momentum this scattering term
在这里，它随着时间刻度tau呈指数下降到零动量，所以它是
here slows it down exponentially to zero
momentum with a time scale tau so it's
就像是阻力，所以理论上的直觉想法是您对待散射
like a drag so that the idea of the dru
to theory is that you treat scattering
作为拖延力量，试图减慢一切或阻碍一切
as a drag force that tries to slow
everything down or hinder it's it's
运动，我想我们会停在那儿，然后我们将撤回理论
motion and I guess we will stop there
and we'll pick up withdrew the theory
下次我明天见
next time I'll see you tomorrow
[掌声]
[Applause]